hello
today we are going to see how to automate thuamcraft 4 infusion using Steve's factory manager
so, once we built an infusion altar stable enough
we can start with the automation
by the way try to get the stability as high as you can
since the automation benefits a lot from extra stability
anyways, to get started
we want an accessible interface to drop the crafted items and a chest where the interface will drop ingredients
once everything is prepared
we can drop the machine inventory manager and connect it to everything
it is enough for the cables to touch all of the wanted inventories from any side
the altar doesn't care about the symmetry
we can check that the cable connected to everything by creating an output on the SFM controller
however managing the pedestals like that is going to be annoying
so we can use a labeler to rename the blocks we will be interacting with
the first and most important is the pedestal in the middle
which we'll show name accordingly
and we can see that we can now easily identify in our controller
but to keep the items balanced on the pedestals
we want to rename all of them
and to make things easier
we rename them in the order we want them to be filled
here is an example
but just go in the order you would normally fill the pedestals while doing infusion
and now time to start our program
we could use some better trigger
but we are going with the default timed one
we can set the timing as we want
more frequent causes more lag but works faster
next we have to move the items on the pedestals
to make things clean and nice
we can use a command group
this is basically a subprogram
that will make a lot of instruction take only a single block of space
to interact with the flow of the upper program
we can use group nodes inputs and outputs
now that we have our nice group for filling the pedestals
we have to actually do the item insertion
we start by creating an input
which will take items as input from the chest
then one by one we add all of the outputs
we go in sequential order to fill all of the pedestals
starting from the middle one
and to make that work
we must make patterns with the middle item as first in the pattern
and we fill the subgroup with all the outputs in sequential order
with that done we can go back to the actual program
and before doing anything else
we will want a condition
that will check if there are any items already present on the altar
we are going to do this check before anything else
to make it work we select all of the pedestals
to make it match any possible item
we select one random item but in match all mode
right click to open the menu
now, if there are no items on the altar
we can proceed with inserting a new crafting
and to ensure that so far everything works
we can already try to craft something
as you can see
the items are already placed with the main in the middle
and the others in a balanced pattern
to automatically start the infusion
we need an infusion claw
equipped with a wand that has some vis inside
and to make it work
it needs a Redstone signal to start the infusion
so we add a Redstone emitter which we properly rename
to control it we add a Redstone emitter to our program
we select the emitter
and set it to output a strong signal
and that shall be done after the items are placed on the pedestals
then we add a second emitter
with strength to 0 to shut it off
for the moment we shall turn it off once the pedestals have been filled and infusion already started
and to avoid having the Redstone emitter always on
we add a condition that will start the process only if there are items ready
otherwise it shut off the starting signal
and now it is time to test if this works
the starting Redstone signal barely made into the video
since it went off as soon as I closed the terminal
but the process is starting
after the long animation of the claw
the long animation of the infusion starts
and after all of the essential and items are collected
we get our item
now we only have to add a couple of instructions to retrieve those
but before retrieving any item
we must be sure the infusion is completed
to do so we make a condition
that will check for items in any of the pedestal but the mid one
we shall make that check after the more generic one
and if it is false or better there are no secondary items
then we can pull out the crafted item on the mid pedestal
so we take as input the mid pedestal
and we output to the interface to complete the crafting that AE2 is waiting
and now we can do a test run
where we can see that everything works fine
or maybe the items was extracted too quickly
the main issue now is that this speed is hardly acceptable for an automated setup
so we add a couple of world accelerator in tile entity mode
those will use 12 amps of the used tier
which might be a lot for some people
so we can add a machine controller cover
to toggle those on only when needed
we turn them on when the infusion is started
and then we turn those off when the items are retrieved from the infusion
and here we also turn off the claw
since we must ensure it toggles on and off to properly work
and now time to see if this is fast enough
and I'd say it's good enough
finally we make a more sustained test
to check if everything works fine
and after a little bit of debugging
it works well enough
the only thing left to do is to make sure we do not lack of essence when we autocraft
we can do that by using an advanced provider
but I never fiddled with it
or, a different approach is to set a slightly higher timer delay
and extract the middle item regardless of the how the process is doing
to stop anything that could have gone wrong
also you can have an input redstone signal to inhibit the automation
and turn on the world accelerator for some rare occasion where you will want to do manual infusions
大家好
今天我们将看到如何使用SFM自动神秘4注魔
那么，一旦我们建了一个足够稳定的注魔祭坛
我们可以开始自动化了
顺便说一句，要让稳定性尽可能高
因为自动化从额外的稳定性中受益匪浅
不管怎样，开始吧
我们想要一个输出原料的ME接口
和一个可以输入原料的箱子
一旦一切准备就绪
我们放下工厂管理器
并将其连接到所有东西上
线缆能接触到要连接的方块的任何一面就行
祭坛不在乎对称性
我们可以通过在SFM控制器上创建输出
来检查线缆是否连接到所有东西
然而，这样管理基座会很烦人
我们可以使用贴标器来重命名要交互的方块
第一个也是最重要的是中间的基座
我们打上相应的名称
现在就可以很容易地在管理器中认出它
但是为了保持基座上物品的平衡
我们要把所有这些重命名了
为了让事情更轻松
我们按照"希望填充它们的顺序"重命名它们
比如下面这个例子
只要按照你一般注魔时填充基座的顺序就可以
现在是时候开始写我们的程序了
我们可以用更好的触发器
但我们要使用默认计时的
我们可以随心所欲地设定时间
更频繁会导致更多卡顿，但工作速度更快
接下来我们必须移动基座上的物品
为了让面板看起来更清爽
我们可以使用命令组
这基本上是一个子程序
这将使大量指令只占用一块空间
要与上层程序的流程交互
我们可以使用输入和输出的组节点
现在我们有了一个很好的、用来填充基座的命令组
我们必须真正地写出插入物品的命令
我们首先创建一个输入模块
它将箱子里的物品作为输入
然后我们一个接一个地添加所有输出
我们按顺序填满所有的基座
从中间开始
为了让它发挥作用
我们的样板必须要把祭坛中间的物品第一个输出
我们按顺序把命令组里的所有的输出写好
完成后，我们可以回到主程序
在做其他任何事情之前
我们需要一个条件模块
来检查祭坛上是否已经有任意物品
这个检查必须要放在做其他操作之前
为此，我们选择了所有的基座
使其匹配任何可能的物品
我们随便选一个物品，打开"匹配所有"模式
右键打开菜单来进行这项设置
那么，如果祭坛上没有东西
我们可以做新的一批合成
要确保到目前为止一切正常
我们已经可以尝试制作一些东西
如你所见
主要的物品已经放在中间了
其他的物品呈现对称的样式放置
要自动开始注魔
我们需要一个注魔爪
里面有一根有vis的魔杖
要让注魔爪工作
它需要红石信号开始注魔
所以我们添加了一个红石发射器，打上了一个合适的名字
为了控制它，我们在程序中添加了一个红石发射器模块
我们选择发射器
并将其设置为输出强信号
输出指令会在物品放到基座上后进行
然后我们添加第二个发射器模块
强度设置为0以关闭它
目前，一旦填充过基座并且开始了注魔，我们将关闭注魔爪
并避免红石发射器始终打开
我们添加了一个条件，仅当有物品准备好时才会启动该过程
否则它会关闭启动信号
现在是时候测试这是否有效了
开始注魔的红石信号几乎没有进入视频
因为我一关闭终端它的强度就被设置成0了
但这个过程正在开始
在注魔爪的漫长动画之后
注魔的漫长动画开始了
在收集到所有的源质和物品后
我们得到了注魔输出
现在我们只需要加几个指令来取出产品
但在取回任何物品之前
我们必须确保注魔完成
为此，我们用一个条件模块
检查除中间基座外的任何基座是否含有物品
我们将在检查所有基座之后再进行该检查
如果输出是假，就说明没有次要物品
然后我们可以把中间底座上合成好的东西拿出来
所以我们把中间基座作为输入
输出到ME接口，以完成AE正在等待的合成
现在我们可以试运行了
一切正常
或许物品提取得太快了
现在的主要问题是，这速度对于自动化来说难以接受
所以我们添加了几个方块实体模式的世界加速器
这些将使用12 A的机器所在电压的电
这对某些人来说可能很多
所以我们可以添加一个机器控制覆盖板
仅在需要时打开加速器
我们在开始注魔时打开它们
然后在取出注魔好的物品时关闭它们
我们此时也关闭注魔爪
因为我们必须确保它打开和关闭以正常工作
现在是时候看看这是否足够快了
这样就差不多了
最后我们做一个更持久的测试
检查是否一切正常
经过一点调试
它工作得很好
唯一要做的就是确保合成时不缺乏源质
我们可以通过使用高级注魔供应器来做到这一点
但我从没研究过这东西
或者，另一种方法是设置稍高的定时器延迟
不管流程进行到哪，强制取出中间基座的物品
阻止任何可能出错的事情
你还可以输入红石信号来暂停自动化
并在需要进行手动注魔的罕见场合打开世界加速器
（这一步可以通过变量模块来简化，创建一个包含所有基座的变量，这样就只需要在一个输入模块里选择这个变量作为输出）
（任何一个基座有物品为真，除中间基座外的任何基座有物品为假，推断出只有中间基座有物品）